<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Saeed&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://smoqadam.me/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Saeed&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 14:36:29 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smoqadam.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Books I Loved Most in 2021</title>
      <link>https://smoqadam.me/posts/books-i-loved-most-in-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 14:36:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smoqadam.me/posts/books-i-loved-most-in-2021/</guid>
      <description>In terms of reading, 2021 was a productive year for me. I read several books, here is the list of those that I loved most.
Outliers: The Story of Success When the books I had ordered online were delivered to me, I saw the Outliers were also in the package. I was disappointed because I hadn’t ordered this, and after contacting the seller, he said he mistakenly put this book instead of another book that I’d ordered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Being Human</title>
      <link>https://smoqadam.me/posts/on-being-human/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 20:33:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smoqadam.me/posts/on-being-human/</guid>
      <description>The human being is a strange species. A creature that has been around for a few million years and since the beginning has been trying to find its way through evolution by its intelligence. Being smart helped us overcome many difficulties, and being selfish made it easier for us to destroy everything to be more dominant. Although we call ourselves the most intelligent species on earth, yet it takes us a few years to learn to walk and interact with other human beings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To remember during the bad days</title>
      <link>https://smoqadam.me/posts/to-remember-during-the-bad-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 21:23:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smoqadam.me/posts/to-remember-during-the-bad-days/</guid>
      <description>It won&amp;rsquo;t last.
You have felt other things. You will feel other things again.
Emotions are like weather. They change and shift. Clouds can seem as still as stone. We look at them and hardly notice a change at all. And yet they always move.
The worst part of any experience is the part where you feel like you can&amp;rsquo;t take it any more. So, if you feel like you can&amp;rsquo;t take it any more, the chances are you are already at the worst point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing the Dishes as an Act of Mindfullness</title>
      <link>https://smoqadam.me/posts/doing-the-dishes-as-an-act-of-mindfullness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 22:48:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smoqadam.me/posts/doing-the-dishes-as-an-act-of-mindfullness/</guid>
      <description>I don’t know why, but for me doing the dishes is one the worst aspect of life, especially when you have to do it after one of the best aspects of life, eating. Since I’ve been struggling to wash the dishes as soon as I use them, the result has always been a sink full of dirty and stinky dishes.
I have tried many ways to overcome this laziness. One of those ways is to look at it as an act of mindfulness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Obstacle Is the Way by Ryan Holiday - Highlights</title>
      <link>https://smoqadam.me/posts/the-obstacle-is-the-way-by-ryan-holiday-highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 16:08:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smoqadam.me/posts/the-obstacle-is-the-way-by-ryan-holiday-highlights/</guid>
      <description>you can focus your energy exclusively on solving problems, rather than reacting to them.    When you worry, ask yourself, What am I choosing to not see right now?    We are A-to-Z thinkers, fretting about A, obsessing over Z, yet forgetting all about B through Y.    Think progress, not perfection.    Okay, you’ve got to do something very difficult. Don’t focus on that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A few ideas for your next Go project</title>
      <link>https://smoqadam.me/posts/a-few-ideas-for-your-next-go-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 15:23:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smoqadam.me/posts/a-few-ideas-for-your-next-go-project/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever been out of idea on what to code for your next open-source or side-project? As a beginner, you can find many resources and tutorials on different beginner-friendly projects out there. But when you pass that level, you just cannot come up with any interesting ideas to work on while you&amp;rsquo;re learning.
You can take any of these ideas for your next project, and dont&#39; forget the purpose of doing this, is learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Man&#39;s Search for Meaning by Victor Frankl - Highlights</title>
      <link>https://smoqadam.me/posts/mans-search-for-meaning-highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 16:08:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smoqadam.me/posts/mans-search-for-meaning-highlights/</guid>
      <description>Nietzsche: “He who has a Why to live for, can bear almost any How.”    Life is not primarily a quest for pleasure, as Freud believed, or a quest for power, as Alfred Adler taught, but a quest for meaning.    The greatest task for any person is to find meaning in his or her life.    Frankl saw three possible sources for meaning: in work (doing something significant), in love (caring for another person), and in courage during diffcult times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 in a Nutshell</title>
      <link>https://smoqadam.me/posts/2020-in-a-nutshell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 21:23:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smoqadam.me/posts/2020-in-a-nutshell/</guid>
      <description>In March 2020, the government announced a lockdown. No one allows to go out except for shopping, and everyone must work from home. First of all, despite of the hard situation for every business, I was lucky that I didn’t get laid off and my salary remained untouched.
After a few days of passing time at home, playing video games, and watching movies, I felt guilty that I’m not as productive as I should be and I’m not using my time efficiently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Simple Deployer with Go by Using the Github Webhooks</title>
      <link>https://smoqadam.me/posts/build-a-simple-deployer-in-go-by-usin-github-hooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 16:58:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smoqadam.me/posts/build-a-simple-deployer-in-go-by-usin-github-hooks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my journey to learn Go, I decided to start write about the topics that I&amp;rsquo;m learning. This technique known as Feynman Learning Technique. I have done this long time ago when I wanted to learn PHP, I started a blog in Persian, and start to write about everything I was learning about PHP. These articles might not be useful for experienced programmers, but it helps me to have a deep understanding about the stuff I&amp;rsquo;m going to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I want to write a simple deployer by using Github Webhooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, please let me know if you find any issues or mistakes. We can disscuss about it and we can learn together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write a PHP Youtube video downloader</title>
      <link>https://smoqadam.me/posts/how-download-youtube-videos-by-php/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 21:37:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smoqadam.me/posts/how-download-youtube-videos-by-php/</guid>
      <description>PHP is not the best language for writing a download manager, but in this article, we are going to learn how we can download videos from Youtube. Because PHP does not support multithreading, we cannot make a proper download manager that split the file into several chunks and download it concurrently. There are some ways to add multithreading to PHP, but for the sake of this article, we won&amp;rsquo;t go through those ways and will stick to single threading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Authenticate User in Symfony 5 by Jwt</title>
      <link>https://smoqadam.me/posts/how-to-authenticate-user-in-symfony-5-by-jwt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:11:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smoqadam.me/posts/how-to-authenticate-user-in-symfony-5-by-jwt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, when we are talking about web development, regardless of the type of application or the programming language, one of the first things that come to mind is how to authenticate users. There are many types of authentication ways for this purpose such as login form, oAuth, JWT, API token, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reliability, security, easy to use and widely supported in many platform and languages make JWT one of the most popular authentication protocols in the web ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we will learn how to implement JWT in Symfony 5 by using the &lt;strong&gt;firebase/php-jwt&lt;/strong&gt; package and AbstractGuardAuthenticator class. There are some bundles or packages already out there like &lt;strong&gt;lexik/LexikJWTAuthenticationBundle&lt;/strong&gt; that we can use but at the end of this tutorial, we will learn how can we implement and use Authentication Guard which in Symfony.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Learned in 2018</title>
      <link>https://smoqadam.me/posts/what-i-learned-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 20:10:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smoqadam.me/posts/what-i-learned-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>Today is the last day of 2018. This year, at least for me, was full of exciting events with an abundance of interesting happenings, which I feel makes me a better person going into 2019. Here are some of my experiences in the past year.
Loneliness can’t hurt you, if you don’t want Actually, I learned it a couple of years ago, but sometimes you can forget about something important so much that maybe it will not hurt you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple auto deployer with PHP</title>
      <link>https://smoqadam.me/posts/simple-auto-deployer-with-php/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 16:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smoqadam.me/posts/simple-auto-deployer-with-php/</guid>
      <description>How you deploy your projects? Are you using fancy things like Jenkins with lots of features and configuration that you don&amp;rsquo;t even know about? For one of my personal projects, I needed to have a deployment tools. I tried to install and configure Jenkins but there was no chance to make it up and running. So I decided to write my own, simple deployer with PHP.
Git Hooks For this article we are using Git hooks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
